- 嗨 各位    - 嗨
- Hey, guys.     - Hey.
亲爱的 我这个周末 在坞福酒店订了房间
Honey, I got us that room at the Woodford Inn this weekend.
在佛蒙特的那个地方？你懂得暗示了
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
你们这个周末不能离开 艾玛的生日到了
You can't go away this weekend. It's Emma's birthday.
- 对   - 我们要开生日派对
- Yeah.    - We're having a party.
派对不能等我们回来再开吗？
Can't you have the party when we get back?
- 不行   - 那就不是她真正的生日了
- No.    - No. It won't be her real birthday.
天啊 但愿一岁的小孩 知道生日是什么东西
Gee, if only she were 1 and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
你们别这样嘛 这对我们真的很重要
Come on, you guys, this is really important to us.
抱歉 但是钱德和我 真的需要好好度个周末
Sorry, but Chandler and I could really use a weekend away...
你知道的 重新培养感情等等   - 还有一些两人一起做的事
...you know, to reconnect, emotionally.     - There's this thing I really want us to do.
我在《格官》上读到的
I read about it in Maxim.
你们不能第二天再去佛蒙特吗？
Well, can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
对 我们希望大家都在
Yeah, we want everyone to be there.
虽然我讨厌耽搁你和我小妹 从事怪异性行为
As much as I hate to delay your doing weird sex stuff to my little sister.
而且 各位 这是很重要的
And, I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
她的第一个生日派对
I mean, how can we have her first birthday party...
姑姑和姑丈怎能不到场呢？
...without her aunt and her uncle?
好吧 我们留下来吧 等派对结束后再去吧
All right, we'll stay. We can just drive up after the party.
好吧 但如果因为派对 我们没做《格官》上教的动作…
Fine. But if we end up not doing this Maxim thing because of this party...
相信我 我们没做不是因为那个原因
Believe me, that is not why we won't be doing that.
菲比 我小的时候 每当生日时
You know, Pheebs, when I was little, on my birthday...
我爸会在屋里每个房间 都藏个礼物
...my daddy would hide a present in every room of the house.
然后他会画个宝藏图 让我把它们一一找出来
And then he would draw a treasure map to help me find them all.
我最喜欢像那样的家庭传统了
Aw, I love family traditions like that.
乌苏扛和我小的时候 每当生日时
When Ursula and I were kids, on our birthday...
我们的继父就会去卖血 为我们买食物
...our stepdad would sell his blood to buy us food.
- 嗨 各位   - 嗨
- Hey, guys.     - Hi.
- 我带摄影机来拍要给艾玛的影片   - 太好了
- I brought the camera for Emma's video.     - Oh, good!
我们想拍个生日短片
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma...
等艾玛十八岁时送给她   - 太酷了
...and we'll give it to her when she's 18.     - Oh, cool.
- 这就像时光胶囊一样    - 没错
- Wow, it's like a time capsule.     - Yeah.
想想看 她将在 现在还没发明的电视上…
Oh, just think, she's gonna be watching that video on a TV...
看这部影片
...that hasn't even been invented yet...
和那些现在还是婴儿的朋友一起看
...with friends who, right now, are just, like, babies.
他们将住在人类造来…
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built...
逃避蚂蚁人的空中之城里
...to escape the ant people.
最好是这样
That's the hope.
- 艾玛醒来了吗？ - 还没 现在还是午睡时问
- So is Emma awake yet?     - No, it's still naptime.
- 但她应该很快会醒来   - 那么乔伊呢？
- But she'll be up soon.     - Where's Joey?
我说过了 现在还是午睡时问
I said, it's still naptime.
- 乔伊叔叔来了   - 嗨
- Hey, there's Uncle Joey.     - Hey.
说些话 祝艾玛十八岁生日快乐吧
Hey, say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
- 十八岁？ - 乔伊 不要这样
- Eighteen, huh?     - Joey, no!
干嘛？是给她那些性感的朋友
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
当她们看到这个影片时 你已经五十二岁了
When they see this, you'll be 52.
而且开始想要定下来了
And starting to think about settling down.
乔伊 你可以帮忙把这架起来 让大家放送艾玛的礼物吗？
Hey, Joey, will you please set this up for people to put Emma's presents on?
非常乐意
Love to. Yeah.
- 我们应该要送礼物吗？ - 对 我为艾玛写了首歌
- We were supposed to bring presents?     - Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
是啊 我怎么会知道呢？
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
- 乔伊 这是个生日派对   - 我知道 但她只有一岁
- Joey, it's a birthday party.     - Yeah, but for a 1 -year-old.
这有什么意义？那天他对着杯子大笑一个多小时 只是一个普通杯子
What's the point? The other day she laughed for, like, an hour at a cup.
只因为杯子上有艾摩 穿得像农夫的照片
Just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it, dressed as a farmer.
他站在一头牛的旁边 然后牛说"艾…摩"
And he's standing next to this cow, and the cow says, "El-moo."
天啊 那真是个好笑的杯子
Man, that's a funny cup.
嗨
Hey.
- 生日女孩呢？ - 她还在睡午觉
- Where's the birthday girl?     - Oh, she's still napping.
她昨晚一定是因为今天的派对 而兴奋到睡不着
She was probably up all night excited about the party she knows is happening.
我知道你们真的很想去佛蒙特 而这对你们而言也没什么大不了
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont, and this isn't a big deal to you.
但这对我们真的很重要 好吗？艾玛不会再有周岁生日了
But it really is to us, okay? Emma will never have a first birthday again.
你说得对 我们很抱歉
You're right. We're sorry.
我们去把艾玛叫醒 开始庆祝吧
Let's wake up Emma and get the fun time started!
不行 她昨晚没睡好 所以我们不能吵醒她
No, she didn't sleep well last night, so we can't wake her.
你在跟我开玩笑吗 葛林小姐？
Are you frigging kidding me, Green?
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi!     - Hey!
- 真高兴你们能来   - 我不敢相信艾玛已经一岁了
- I'm so glad you came.     - I can't believe Emma's already 1.
我记得你一岁生日的时候
I remember your first birthday.
罗斯忌妒我们只注意你
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
他好用力的扯自己的小弟弟
He pulled on his testicles so hard...
结果我们只好带他到医院挂急诊
...we had to take him to the emergency room.
老爸总有新鲜事
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
盖勒先生 盖勒太太 我帮你们拿吧
Hey, Mr. And Mrs. Geller. Let me help you with that.
- 谢谢你   - 天啊 这真是太棒了 对吗？
- Thank you.     - Oh, man, this is great, huh?
我们三个又聚在一起了 你们知道怎样会更好玩吗？
The three of us together again. You know what would be fun?
就是我们三个 一起送艾玛这个礼物
If we gave this present to Emma from all of us.
你到底是谁？
Which one are you?
- 我不敢相信艾玛还在睡觉   - 对啊 我们该怎么办？
- I can't believe Emma's still asleep.     - I know. What are we gonna do?
我想到了…
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我会很用力地 把这个盘子撞向你的肋骨
I'm going to ram this platter really hard into your ribs.
然后你大叫 那就会把她吵醒了
You're gonna scream out, and that'll wake her up.
我不跟这个摩妮卡去佛蒙特
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
菲比 你知道吗？
Hey, Pheebs? You know what?
我在想既然你写了首歌
I was thinking since you wrote a song...
或许我可以用我的天分 送艾玛礼物
...maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
所以你要把她吗？
So you're gonna hit on her?
- 当然不是 是我演戏的天分   - 噢
- No, no, no. My talents as an actor.     - Oh.
或许我可以…
You know, I could, like, maybe...
我可以感性地为她读本故事书
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
或者你可以拿叉子插到苹果里
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
- 我觉得艾玛可能会喜欢   - 艾玛会喜欢什么？
- Hey, I think Emma might like it.     - Oh, Emma might like what?
- 我的礼物   - 你为她准备了什么？
- Uh, my present.     - What did you get her?
- 我们准备要表演   - 个别表演
- Actually, we prepared performances.     - Separate performances.
但一样有诚意
But equally real.
听起来好像很好玩
That sounds like fun.
大家等艾玛醒来
You know what, actually?
好像等得有点不耐烦了
People are getting a little antsy waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
所以你介意 现在先为他们表演一次吗？
So would you mind performing them once now?
- 当然可以   - 好啊
- Sure, yeah!     - Okay.
好了 各位 派对开始了
Okay. All right. Everybody, let's get this party started, huh?
乔伊和菲比将要为大家表演
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
太好了
Oh, great.
什么都没有准备 你不会不好意思吗？
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed having nothing prepared?
我每个星期都这样 外加三台摄影机和整组人盯着我
I do it every week with three cameras pointed at me and a whole crew waiting.
乔伊 你要为我们表演什么？
So, Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
我要感性地为艾玛读本故事书
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
好吧 哪一本呢？
Oh, okay. Which one?
她最爱的那一本
Uh, well, it's one of her favorites.
《度过难关 如何处理产后忧郁症》
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
《永远爱你》
Love You Forever.
《永远爱你》 作者罗伯马修 萤火虫出版社
"Love You Forever, by Robert Munsch. Published by Firefly Books. Printed...
墨西哥印制
...in Mexico.
一位妈妈抱着她刚出生的小宝宝 轻轻地把他搂在怀里
Ahem. A mother held her new baby and very slowly rocked him...
轻轻地摇啊摇…
...back and forth, back and forth, back and forth.
轻轻地唱着 我永远爱你
And while she held him, she sang, 'I'll love you forever.
我永远疼你 在妈妈的心里
I'll like you for always. As long as I'm living...
你是我永远的宝贝
...my baby you'll be."'
轻轻地摇啊摇 她轻轻的唱起了
"And while he rocked her, he sang:
我永远爱你 我永远疼你
'I'll love you forever. I'll like you for always.
在爸爸的心里
As long as I'm living...
你是我永远的宝贝
...my baby you'll be."'
哦 哇哦
Oh, wow!
真是太感人了
That was amazing.
非常感谢你的礼物
Thank you so much for that gift.
我今天还没准备好接受这种刺激
I was not ready for this today.
- 太感人了…   - 菲比 抱歉
- Amazing. Amazing.     - Phoebe, I'm sorry.
- 菲比也准备了表演   - 没错
- Phoebe has prepared something.     - That's right.
我发自内心为艾玛写了首歌
I prepared a song for Emma, from my heart to hers.
没有任何礼物比得上音乐
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
艾玛
Emma
你的名字诉说着困境
Your name poses a dilemma
跟"安娜"又不同音
'Cause not much else rhymes with Emma
或许是李察克雷那
Maybe the actor, Richard Crenna
他在《第一滴血》演指挥官
He played the commanding officer in Rambo.
祝你生日快乐 艾玛
Happy birthday, Emma
就那样？
Is that it?
不是 当然不只
No, of course not.
不只这个 我还准备了朗读
No, I've also, you know, prepared a reading.
《单亲妈妈的性生活》
Um, "Sex and the Single Mother."
- "发现你的高潮点"   - 别念了…
- "Finding your G-spot."     - Oh, no, no, no!
艾玛 十八岁生日快乐
Hello, Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
现在看起来似乎好遥远 还有十七年
Right now, that seems so far away, 17 years.
没错 到时你将长得亭亭玉立 而我们将…
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then, and we'll be...
你的祖父和我可能不在了
Well, your grandfather and I might not be here.
没错 这讯息可能会从坟墓里
That's true. This message could be coming to you...
传送给你 艾玛
...from beyond the grave, Emma.
- 毕竟我的父母走得很早   - 而我的胆固醇已破表了
- After all, my parents died very young.     - And my cholesterol's off the charts.
记得 艾玛 心脏疾病也会杀死女人的
Remember, Emma, heart disease kills women too.
好了 停 很好…那真是…
Okay, cut! Great. Great. That was just...
- 好吧   - 很好
- Yeah.     - Oh, good.
罗斯 别忘了拍一下艾玛的蛋糕
Ross, uh, don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
- 就在冰箱里的盒子     - 好 没问题
- It's in a box in the fridge.   - Okay, sure.
你一定会爱死这个蛋糕 我在新泽西的凯莉诺面包店买的
You're gonna love this cake. I got it from a bakery in New Jersey, Carino's.
天啊 那里有最浓郁的糖霜
Oh, my God, that place has the creamiest frosting.
我小的时候常搭便车去那里
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
好 他们有许多不同形状 新颖小巧的蛋糕
Well, anyway, they make these great novelty cakes...
如果给他们照片 他们会用糖衣翻印
...in all different shapes. And if you give them a photo, they'll copy it in icing.
- 你用艾玛的照片去做了？ - 是的 印在兔宝宝形状的蛋糕上
- Did you do a picture of Emma?     - Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
瑞秋 这家面包店是否也有做…
Uh, Rach? Does this bakery by any chance also bake...
情趣蛋糕？
...erotic cakes?
例如 给告别单身女子派对用的？
Say, for bachelorette parties?
罗斯 你在胡说些…？我的天啊
Ross, what are you talking...? Oh, my God!
他们把我宝贝的脸放在小弟弟上了
They put my baby's face on a penis!
这才像是个派对
Now it's a party!
等一下 各位 这并不好笑
Wait, you guys, this isn't funny, all right?
如果我要用蛋糕来破坏派对 我自己做就可以了
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster, I would have baked it myself!
我可以认为这看起来蛮好吃的吗？
Uh... Is it okay that I still think it looks delicious?
- 杰克 你看这个   - 我知道你在想什么 茱蒂
- Jack, look at this.     - I know what you're thinking, Judy.
这相似度太不可思议了
The resemblance is uncanny.
我已经又快要拉我的小弟弟了
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
不…这不是我订的 好吗？
No, no, this is not what I ordered, okay?
我大老远跑到新泽西 就是为了替我的女儿
I went all the way to New Jersey so that I could have the perfect cake...
买个完美的生日蛋糕 我现在就要我的兔宝宝蛋糕
...for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
问他们这样会不会快一点 如果把宝宝的脸从小弟弟上切下来
Ask them if it would be faster if we cut the baby's face off the penis...
然后我们可以把它放在兔宝宝上
...so we could put it on the bunny.
这听起来真奇怪
That is a weird sentence.
你相信我 我会把这个蛋糕送回去的
Oh, believe you me, I am going to bring this cake back.
我根本不想要它出现在我家 乔伊 不要碰它
I don't even want it in my home. Don't touch it!
我好困惑哦
I'm so confused!
是的 我还是要有我女儿的照片 但是要在兔宝宝蛋糕上
Yes, I still want my daughter's picture, but on a bunny cake!
黄色的蛋糕 上面有巧克力糖霜和坚果
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
老实说 这个也有果子啊
To be fair, this one does have nuts.
摩妮卡 你真好 肯把车借给瑞秋
Hey, Mon, it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car...
让她可以去拿蛋糕   - 她更好 抓着我的头发
...so she could get the cake.     - It was nice of her to pull my hair...
逼我交出钥匙
...till I dropped the key.
既然我们都要等 不如就来录…
Well, while we're waiting, you could tape your message to Emma...
你们要给艾玛十八岁的生日留言 好吗？
...for her 18th birthday, huh? Okay?
艾玛 现在是2020年
Hi, Emma. It's the year 2020.
你还是喜欢睡午觉吗？
Are you still enjoying your nap?
对了 我们是摩妮卡姑姑和钱德姑丈
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler, by the way.
你可能不认识我们
You may not recognize us...
因为我们已经十七年 没和你父母讲话了
...because we haven't spoken to your parents in 17 years.
我们本来是夫妇
We used to be married.
但我们错过了一次周末假期 一切都被破坏了
But then we missed a weekend away together, and things kind of unraveled...
这都是你害的
...because of you.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
罗斯 瑞秋答应我们 此时派对早该结束的
Ross, Rachel promised it would be over by now.
如果我们要去佛蒙特 我们真的该走了
We seriously have to go if we want to get to Vermont.
- 最后一班火车半小时后离开   - 我有个按摩的客人就快来了
- The last train leaves in a half-hour.     - And I have a massage client soon.
各位 拜托 再等一下
You guys, just, please, a little bit longer.
我保证瑞秋马上就带蛋糕回来了
I promise, Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
摩妮卡 记得那些糖霜吗？
Monica, remember the frosting, huh?
好吧 再等五分钟
All right, five more minutes.
喂？
Hello?
天啊 怎么了？
Oh, no, what happened?
好… 你在哪里？
Okay, okay, where are you?
好 我 马上过去
Okay, I'll be right there.
是艾玛吗？她醒来了吗？
Was that Emma? Is she up?
瑞秋因为超速 被拦下来了
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
她忘了带驾照 我现在要拿去给她
She forgot her license. So I have to bring it to her.
- 如果你走了 那我也要走了   - 等一下 要走也是我们
- If you're leaving, I'm definitely going.     - Wait, if anybody gets to go, it's us!
我们抱怨最久
We've been complaining the longest!
不 等一下 各位 你们都不能走
No, wait, you guys. No, you can't leave.
因为蛋糕的事 瑞秋已经很难过了
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
如果她回来后看到你们都走了 她的感觉会是如何？
How do you think she'll feel when she comes back and you're gone?
我不知道 你星期一再告诉我们吧
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
乔伊 你负责 好吗？不可以让任何人离开
Joey, you're in charge, okay? You make sure nobody leaves.
没问题
Got it!
嘿 你要去哪里？
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
去厕所
To the bathroom.
其他人休息一下
Well, the rest of you get comfortable, okay...
因为我们还要再等…
...because we are gonna be here for a...
- 等一下 那里面有窗户   - 可恶 他别想那么轻易逃走
- Wait, there's a window in there.     - Oh, no! He's not getting away that easy!
你们要干什么？滚出去
What are you doing? Get the hell out of here!
那一个没有艾玛的脸在上面
Well, that one did not have Emma's face on it.
- 对 没有   - 对
- No, it did not.     - No.
我们要走了 太晚了
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
杰克不能在晚上开车
Jack's not allowed to drive at night anymore.
他会见来见去
He has trouble staying in his lane.
去年冬天我开上教堂的草地冲过马槽的圣诞布置
Last winter I went up on a church lawn and drove right through a manger scene.
报纸把这报导成宗教仇恨
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
- 好了 很高兴见到你们   - 好
- Anyway, it was lovely seeing you.     - Okay.
- 再见 亲爱的   - 晚安
- Bye. Bye, dear.     - Nighty-night.
- 晚安   - 再见
- Nighty-night.     - Bye.
- 你怎么可以让他们走？ - 拜托
- How could you just let them leave?     - Hey, hey.
我不会为难杰克的 他是个好人 他曾为我们国家奋战过
I'm not gonna mess with Jack. He's a great man. He fought for our country.
不 他才没有 他假装是教徒来逃避韩战
No, he didn't. He pretended to be a Quaker to get out of Korea.
好了 够了 他是最后一个了 我要把你们全锁起来
Well, that's it. He's the last one to go. I'm locking you guys in. Ha.
你知道我可以往另外一边转吧？
You do know I can just turn them the other way around, right?
我忘了你住过这里
Oh, I forgot you used to live here.
- 喂？ - 乔伊 我是伊斯特
- Hello?     - Joey, it's Estelle.
- 嗨   - 你今天去试镜结果如何？
- Hey.   - So how'd your audition go today?
- 什么试镜？ - 我上星期跟你说的那个
- What audition?     - The one I told you about last week.
什么？你没有跟我讲过什么试镜啊
What? You never said anything about an audition.
让我重来一次 我刚接到一通电话 叫你去试镜
Let me start over. I just got a call about an audition.
我想你现在赶去还来得及
I think you can still make it.
就在亚斯特剧场 你需要准备一段独白
It's down at the Astor Theater, and you need to have a monologue prepared.
一段独白？我没有…
A monologue? I don't have a...
有了
I got it. Uh...
我要走了
So I'm gonna take off.
- 什么？ - 不 等一下 你不能离开
- What?     - What? Wait! You don't get to leave.
我还有按摩客户在等我
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
我们付钱订了房间 再不去就泡汤了
And we paid for a room that we're supposed to be in right now!
好了
Well, okay, now...
其实我们只要有一个人 留下来陪艾玛就行了
...only one of us has to stay with Emma.
好 既然是我想到的 我可以先走
Okay, and as the person who realized that, I get to go.
不行…
No, no, no. No. No.
我们要想一个公平的方法 决定谁要留下来
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
我想到了
Oh, I got it.
好 一到十 每个人选个号码 好吗？
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to 10, all right?
选到最高号码的人可以先走
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
- 好 10   - 摩妮卡选10 我选9
- Okay, 10.     - Okay, Monica picks 10. I call nine.
还有谁？
Anyone else?
- 不行 我们来抽签吧   - 也好
- No, let's just draw straws.     - Okay.
或者我们可以丢铜板 然后乘以…
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer...
- 我求你别再说了     - 好吧
- I'm begging you to stop.   - Right.
好了 这样如何？ 我们一人选一样艾玛的发条玩具
Okay, how about this? We got wind-up toys for Emma for her birthday.
然后来比赛 最后到达终点的人留下来
We can make them race, and whoever comes in last stays.
好 就这样
Yeah, let's do that!
这听起来 比我们要在佛蒙特玩的更有趣
That sounds more fun than the thing we were gonna do in Vermont!
- 好 各位 选好你的玩具   - 好 我要海豚
- Okay, everybody, pick your toys!     - Okay. I want the dolphin!
- 那是只熊   - 我太兴奋了
- That's a bear.     - I'm too excited!
菲比 你拿熊 乔伊 你拿机器人
Phoebe, you get the bear. Joey, you get the robot.
- 太好了   - 钱德和我拿小狗
- Oh, yeah.     - And Chandler and I get the dog.
比赛从这里走到那里
And the race is going to go from here to here.
最后到达终点的人留下来
Now, the one who comes in last stays!
好 各位女士和先生 上紧发条了
Okay, ladies and gentlemen, wind your toys.
- 好 就定位 预备 开始   - 加油…
- Okay. On your mark, get set, go!     - Go! Go!
加油 机器人
Come on, robot!
你到底在叫什么？
What are you barking at?
那样有帮助吗？
Well, how is that gonna help?
是我买下你的 我怎么忘了你只会那样呢？
I bought you! How did I forget that that's all you do?
太棒了 机器人
Way to go, robot!
干得好 艾伦
Good job, Alan.
- 各位 真是场精彩的比赛   - 没错 待会儿见了
- Hey, good race, you guys.     - Yeah, see you later.
不…等一下
No. No, no. Wait.
我们还没有输
We didn't lose.
规则清楚说明 最后越过终点线的人就输了
The rules clearly stated that the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
我们的狗从没越过终点线 所以 严格来说…
Well, our dog never crossed the finish line. So technically...
他们已经离开了
They left.
时间不够去面包店了 我们要回来了
There isn't time to go to the bakery. We're just gonna come home.
大家都走了？
Everybody left?
好吧 告诉艾玛 我们会尽快赶回来 再见
All right. Well, just tell Emma that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
- 瑞秋   - 天啊 抱歉
- Rachel!     - Oh, God, sorry!
我不敢相信他们居然开你罚单 你是如此优秀的驾驶
I can't believe they gave you a ticket. You're such a good driver.
- 艾玛醒来了   - 是吗？
- Emma's awake.     - Yeah?
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe this.
这是她的第一个生日 现在她醒来了 我们却不在那里
This is her first birthday, she's awake, we're not even there.
大家都走了 我们还抱着这个猥亵又愚蠢的蛋糕
Everybody left. We still have this stupid obscene cake.
或许我可以试着修改看看 看能否把它变成别的东西
Hey, maybe I can fix that. You know, try to turn it into something else.
噢 别烦了
Oh, don't even bother.
我们已经毁了她的第一个生日
We've already ruined her first birthday.
罗斯 你知道这些早年的经验 有多重要吗？非常重要
And do you know how important these early experiences are, Ross? Very!
根据你给我的那本书的封底
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
瑞秋 她不会记得这个的
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
我想是吧
I guess.
我只是原本想着这天应该是…
Oh, I just had such an idea of what this day would be like, you know?
艾玛开心笑着
Emma laughing...
大家聚在一起 围着她的蛋糕 唱着《生日快乐歌》
...and everybody gathered around her cake, singing "Happy Birthday."
然后我们大家… 滚远一点 你这个笨新手驾驶
And then we would all... Hey, get out of the road, you stupid student driver!
他们得学会开车
They have to learn.
- 你看   - 什么？
- Hey.     - What?
这还不错哦
This is not bad.
天啊 你把它变成兔宝宝了 你怎么做的？
Oh, my God. Look, you made it into a bunny. How did you do that?
我把这两粒东西变成脸颊
Well, I just made these two things cheeks.
然后把这切开变成耳朵
And then I split this to make ears.
我太成动了
Well, I am very impressed.
有些人会唱歌 有些人会跳舞
Some can sing, some can dance.
很显然地 我就是能把阴茎的蛋糕 变成森林动物
I, apparently, can turn phallic cakes into woodland creatures.
另一个整理填充玩具的方法 是用大小分类
Now, another way to organize your stuffed animals is by size.
不好意思 这是艾玛的游戏 还是摩妮卡的？
I'm sorry, is this a game for Emma or for Monica?
你说这是游戏？
Game?
艾玛 知道今天是你的生日吗？你一岁了
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today? You're 1.
一岁了 好小哦
One year old. That's little.
这才是我的乖女孩
That's my girl.
没错 你就是这么大
That's how old you are.
是我教她的吗？我刚传授了智慧给她吗？
Did I teach her that? Did I just impart wisdom?
我想要一个
Aw, I want one.
我也是
Me too.
既然现在没有别人 干脆我们带走这个 好吗？
There's no one around. Why don't we just take this one?
- 然后逃去加拿大   - 我是开玩笑的
- And head to Canada.     - I was kidding.
我不是 我们走吧
I wasn't. Let's get going.
- 罗斯和瑞秋回来了吗？ - 没有 还没有
- Hey, are Ross and Rachel back?     - No, not yet.
- 太好了 我没有错过派对   - 你的按摩客人呢？
- Good, I didn't miss the party.     - What about your massage client?
我对错过派对感到过意不去 所以我弄了点东西给他喝
I just felt so bad missing this. So I just slipped him a little something, you know.
只要我在五或六小时内回去 就不会有问题的
As long as I'm back in five or six hours, it'll be all right.
好了
Okay.
如果罗斯和瑞秋问起 要说我一直在这里…
If Ross and Rachel ask, I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
我一直在这里
I've been here the whole time.
乔伊 我们刚看到你进来 你在楼梯间冲过我们
Joey, we just saw you come in. You ran past us on the stairs.
我不介意你们离开过 现在在就好 谢谢你们大家
I don't care that you left. I'm just glad that you're here. Thanks, you guys.
大家过来看看 艾玛刚做了什么
Hey, guys, come on. You gotta see what Emma just did.
- 什么？ - 艾玛 你几岁了？
- What?     - Emma, how old are you?
你今天几岁了？
How old are you today?
艾玛 没错 你一岁了
Oh, Emma, that's right. You're that many.
天啊 我们的女儿是天才
Oh, my God, our daughter's a genius.
- 那表示…   - 不行 不要参加科学营
- This means...     - No! No science camp!
- 可恶 我去把蜡烛插在蛋糕上   - 噢
- Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.     - Oh...
艾玛 你的填充玩具 整理得这么整齐
Oh, and, Emma, look at your stuffed animals lined up so neatly.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了 来吧
Okay, here we go.
艾玛的第一个生日蛋糕
Emma's first birthday cake.
来吧 艾玛 吹蜡烛吧
Go ahead, Emma, blow out the candle.
加油 艾玛 你可以的
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
- 怎么了？你还好吗？ - 还好 没事
- What's wrong? Are you okay?     - Oh, yeah, nothing.
这些是快乐的眼泪
These are happy tears. Ha, ha.
这就是我想要的
This is just what I wanted.
嘿 你把它变成兔宝宝了
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
我是怎么了？竟然认为原本的形状看起来比较好吃
What is wrong with me? It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
- 好了 你准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Okay.Yeah.     - Okay, you ready?
- 开始录影   - 好
- And record.     - Okay.
嗨 艾玛 你的第一个生日已经结束了…
Hi, Emma. Well, your first birthday is over, and...
加油 加油…
Go! Go! Come on!
加油…艾伦 跑快点  你这毛茸茸的混蛋
Go! Go, Alan! Run, you hairy bastard!